A Finding Aid to the Harry Siddons Mowbray and Mowbray Family Papers, 1872-1976, in the Archives of American Art aaa.mowbharr
Archives of American Art
Harry Siddons Mowbray and Mowbray Family papers
1872-1976
aaa.mowbharr
Archives of American Art
7.5 Linear feet
The papers of painter and muralist Harry Siddons Mowbray (1858-1928) and the Mowbray family measure 7.5 linear feet and date from 1872 to 1976. The papers document Mowbray's career as a painter and decorative muralist as well as his activities with the Commission of Fine Arts, the American Academy in Rome, and the Sculpture Commission of Connecticut. The papers include biographical materials, scattered correspondence, nineteen diaries, personal business records, commission files, organization files, writings and notes, printed materials, three scrapbooks, photographs, and artworks. There are scattered family papers of Helen Mowbray, Florence Mowbray, George Mowbray, and George Siddons Mowbray.
Mowbray, H. Siddons (Harry Siddons), 1858-1928
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 11 series. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Series 1: Biographical Information, 1872-1965 (0.4 linear feet; Box 1, 13, 15)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1873-1957 (0.4 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 3: Diaries, 1876-1929 (1.2 linear feet; Box 1-2)
Series 4: Writings and Notes, circa 1870-circa 1930 (0.2 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 5: Personal Business and Financial Records, 1877-1966 (3 folders; Box 3)
Series 6: Commission Files, 1896-1979 (0.4 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 7: Organization Files, 1904-1928 (0.7 linear feet; Box 3-4, 13, 15-16)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1876-1976 (0.2 linear feet; Box 4, 16)
Series 9: Photographs, circa 1874-circa 1928 (4.7 linear feet; Box 4-14, 17-18)
Series 10: Scrapbooks, circa 1890-1920 (0.3 linear feet; Box 5, 13-14)
Series 11: Artwork, 1870-1910 (3 folders; Box 5, 13)
Biographical/Historical note
Harry Siddons Mowbray (1858-1928) was a painter, muralist, and public servant who was active in New York, Connecticut, and Washington, D.C..
Born in Alexandria, Egypt in 1858, Harry Siddons was orphaned at an early age. He was sent to live with his mother's sister Annie and uncle, George Mowbray, whose name he adopted. Harry Siddons Mowbray attended West Point Military Academy but left to pursue a career as a painter. Upon moving to Paris, Mowbray enrolled at the Atelier Bonnant where he studied under Léon Bonnat. Mowbray received attention for his decorative murals thoughout the East Coast of the United States. His commissions included the J.P. Morgan Library, F. W. Vanderbilt house, Larz Anderson house, Appellate Courthouse of New York City, St. John's Church in Washignton Connecticut, and the Federal Building in Cleveland, Ohio. Later in his career, Mowbray returned to painting and completed the Life of Christ series of works.
In addition to painting, Mowbray served on public commissions and committees. He was a member of the federal Commission of Fine Arts from 1921 until his death in 1928. During this time, he was involved in the planning of many Washington, D.C. memorials and public works including the standardization of the flag of the United States of America. He served as director of the American Academy in Rome from 1903-1904.
Harry Siddons Mowbray married Helen Amelia Millard in 1888. They had one child, George Siddons Mowbray. After his wife's death, Mowbray married her sister, Florence in 1915. Together, Florence and Mowbray had two children. He died in 1928. After her husband's death, Florence Mowbray was active in publishing her husband's autobiography.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of painter and muralist Harry Siddons Mowbray (1858-1928) and the Mowbray family measure 7.5 linear feet and date from 1872 to 1976. The papers document Mowbray's career as a painter and decorative muralist as well as his activities with the Commission of Fine Arts, the American Academy in Rome, and the Sculpture Commission of Connecticut. The papers include biographical materials, scattered correspondence, nineteen diaries, personal business records, commission files, organization files, writings and notes, printed materials, three scrapbooks, photographs, and artworks. There are scattered family papers of Helen Mowbray, Florence Mowbray, George Mowbray, and George Siddons Mowbray.
Biographical material includes biographical sketches, certificates, obituaries and estate records, and school material. Also found are printed materials from memorial dedications, ceremonies, and dinners held in Washington, D.C., such as menus, invitations, and admission tickets.
Correspondence is scattered and consists of letters from family, professional colleagues, artists, and architects including Charles McKim and William R. Mead. Florence Mowbray's correspondence includes thank you notes and condolences.
Diaries include seventeen written by Harry Siddons Mowbray, one by Helen Mowbray, and one by Florence Mowbray. Harry Siddons Mowbray's diaries date from 1876 to 1927 and reference a trip to the Azores, current events, his career and works of art, and his service with the Commission of Fine Arts.
Writings and notes consist of Mowbray's handwritten autobiography, school writings, lists, and a biography of Mowbray by Herbert Sherwood.
Personal business records consist of a French military sponsorship, gift acknowledgements and receipts.
Commission files include correspondence, printed materials, and writings relating to Mowbray's works of art at: Larz Anderson House, Appellate Court in New York City; Federal Building in Cleveland, Ohio; Gunn Memorial Library in Washington, CT; the Life of Christ Series; Madison Square Church in New York City; Morgan Library in New York City; St. John's Church in Washington, CT; University Club in New York City; and F. W. Vanderbilt House in Hyde Park, New York.
Organization files document Mowbray's participation with the American Academy in Rome, the Commission of Fine Arts, and the Sculpture Commission of Connecticut. Files generall include organizational history, correspondence, printed material, writings, reports, meeting minutes, and printed material. Of note are materials relating to the standardization of the flag of the United States.
Printed material includes blank stationery and postcards, clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and an issue of Collector's News.
Photographs include two photo albums complied by the Mowbray family, portraits of Mowbray, snapshots with colleagues and friends, and photos of works of art.
One scrapbook compiled by Harry Siddons Mowbray relates to his travels in Rome in 1903-1904. Annother documents his artwork and career, and the third contains clippings concerning his chemical inventions.
Artworks include sketches, prints, and etchings by Harry Siddons Mowbray and others.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Harry Siddons Mowbray and Mowbray family papers were donated in multiple accretions by Mrs. Henry S. Mowbray, Hugh McK. Jones, Jr., and Mrs. Helen M. Rogers from 1979-1983.
Separated Materials note
Material on microfilm reel 2895 was returned to Helen M. Rogers after filming. These materials include Mowbray's letters to his son George, travel diaries of Helen Mowbray, writings, artworks, and a photograph.
American Academy in Rome.; McKim, Charles Follen, 1847-1909; Mead, William Rutherford, 1846-1928; Mowbray, Florence Millard; Mowbray, George Mordey, d. 1891; Mowbray, George S.; Mowbray, Helen Amelia, d. 1910; Pierpont Morgan Library; Sherwood, Herbert F., (Herbert Francis), 1872-; United States. Commission of Fine Arts.; University Club. (New York, N.Y.); Diaries; Etchings; Flags--United States; Larz Anderson Park (Brookline, Mass.); Mural painting and decoration; Muralists--New York (State)--New York; Painters--Connecticut; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Photographs; Prints; Scrapbooks; Sketches
- Biographical Information, 1872-1965; Series 1; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1, 13, 15
  Scope and Contents note
  Most of the biographical material concerns Harry Siddons Mowbray's career as an artist. Found are admissions tickets, menus, programs, and invitations to dedication ceremonies in Washington D.C.; Atelier Bonnant acceptance material; awards; and World War I support material given to Mowbray in thanks for his participation in advocating for the United States' involvement in the war. Other materials include biographical sketches; Mowbray's marriage certificate with his second wife, Florence; obituaries and estate papers; travel papers; and West Point acceptance material and discharge papers. George Mowbray's pocket chemist book is also found.
  - Admissions Tickets, 1918-1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appointment Certificates, 1888-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Oversized material housed in OV15
  - Atelier Bonnant Materials, 1878-1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Awards, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Sketches, after 1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Business and Calling Cards, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Invitations, 1879-1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Marriage Certificate, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Menus, 1884-1901; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Some menus are original etchings and are signed by artists on the back, including Kenyon Cox, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, Stanford White, J. Beckwith, and T. W. Dewing.
  - Programs, 1905-1907 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Obituaries, Funeral Sermons, and Memorials, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Travel Papers, 1874-1878 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - West Point and Military Papers, 1872-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
  - Will and Estate Papers, 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - World War I Support Material, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Oversized material housed in OV13
  - George Mowbray's Chemist Pocket Book, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Oversized World War I Materials, circa 1919 (Box 13)
    Material from Box 1, F20
  - Oversized Appointment Certificates, 1910 (Box 15)
    Material from Box 1, F2
- Correspondence, 1873-1957; Series 2; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1
  This series contains scattered correspondence from artists, colleagues, and art organizations to Harry Siddons Mowbray. Personal correspondence consists of letters from Mowbray's adoptive father and uncle, George Mowbray and some scattered family members. Correspondents include George Mowbray, James Carroll Beckwith, Edwin Blashfield, Bryson Burroughs, Charkes McKim and William R. Mead. Also found are extensive condolence letters and thank you notes written to Florence Mowbray upon her husband's death and for copies of a biography of her husband, respectively. Other letters are to Mowbray's grandson, Harry Siddons Mowbray, Jr.. There is also a letter to Mowbray's son George.
  - A, 1904-1926 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - B, 1909-1922 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - D, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - F, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - G, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - H, 1912-1926 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - I, 1905-1911 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - L, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - M, circa 1910-1926 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Mc, 1902-1926 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Mowbray, George, 1873-1884 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - P, 1911-1924 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - S, 1903-1923 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - T, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - V, 1911-1914 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - W, 1877-1915 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - First Names Only, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Unidentified, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Florence Mowbray and H. Siddons Mowbray Jr. Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Condolence Letters, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 40-43)
    - Thank You Notes--for Mowbray Memorial Book, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 44-47)
    - General, 1928-1957 (Box 1, Folder 48-50)
- Diaries, 1876-1929; Series 3; 1.2 Linear feet Box 1-2
  This series consists of nineteen total diaries, seventeen of which are written by Harry Siddons Mowbray (1876-1927). The additional two diaries are by Elsie Mowbray in (1901) and Florence Mowbray (1929).
  Harry Siddons Mowbray diaries discuss Mowbray's day-to-day life including his relationship with family and friends; his career spanning his service on numerous public art committees and of his works of art; and current events. The first diary (1876) focuses on Mowbray's journey to the Archipelago of the Azores in the Atlantic Ocean. The diaries jump to 1912 and are complete until 1927. From 1912 until 1920, Mowbray gives descriptions of the weather and quick comments on his days. He includes tips for plaster casts (1915). Mowbray's discussion of world affairs includes the sinking of the Titanic the United States' declaration of war in 1917. He relates these larger events by describing their relation to his personal life and family by discussing his colleague Francis Millet's death upon the Titanic and his son's return from World War I.
  Starting in the 1920s, Mowbray focuses his diaries on his service on the Commission of Fine Arts based in Washington, D.C.. These later diaries discuss the construction of Memorial Bridge and Key Bridge and Mowbray's opinions of their location and design; a proposed memorial to be dedicated to President Harding; the process of standardizing the flag of the United States; diplomatic receptions and visits to the White House; the dedication and design of the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier in Arlington Cemetery; the Navy Memorial; public pool placement in the District of Columbia and related racial tension; federal buildings along Pennsylvania Avenue; and the proposed memorial to George Washington at Wakefield House.
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    This diary begins as a notepad for notes, possibly while Mowbray was at West Point, and includes a song and sketches. The diary focuses on a trip to the Azores beginning on July 6, 1876. Included are shipboard sketches as well as vivid descriptions of flying fish, whales, Azores cuisine, and Horta Bay.
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Includes a recipe for mulled wine
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray Diary, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Elsie Mowbray Diary, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Florence Mowbray Diary, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    This diary focuses on a trip to Europe on the SS America.
- Writings and Notes, circa 1870- circa 1930; Series 4; 0.2 Linear feet Box 3
  Writings include an autobiographical manuscript, school writings, and lists written by Mowbray. Other materials include a handwritten copy of a poem by Kenyon Cox and a biography of Mowbray by Herbert Sherwood.
  - Autobiography, Handwritten Manuscript, circa 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Autobiography, Manuscript and Notes, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
  - School Writings, circa 1870 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lists, circa 1920-1966 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Poem, by Kenyon Cox (copy), circa 1900 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Biography of Harry Siddons Mowbray, by Herbert Sherwood, circa 1928 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Personal Business and Financial Records, 1877-1966; Series 5; 3 Folders Box 3
  This series consists of documents relating to a French military sponsorship, gift acknowledgements, and receipts.
  - French Military Sponsorship, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gift to Yale University, 1924-1928 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Receipts, 1966; 1877-1888 (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
- Commission Files, 1896-1979; Series 6; 0.4 Linear feet Box 3
  Commission files include the Larz Anderson House, Appellate Court in New York City; Federal Building in Cleveland, Ohio; Gunn Memorial Library in Washington, CT; the Life of Christ Series; Madison Square Church in New York City; Morgan Library in New York City; St. John's Church in Washington, CT; University Club in New York City; and F. W. Vanderbilt House in Hyde Park, New York. Files contain correspondence, brochures published by the sponsor, clippings, plans and writings. Photographs of these works of art are arranged in Series 9, Photographs.
  - Anderson House, Washington, D.C. (Box 3)
    - Writings, circa 1904 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Society of the Cincinnati Materials, circa 1950-1979 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Appellate Court, New York City, NY (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1896-1900 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Brochure, circa 1896 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Federal Building, Cleveland, OH (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Writings, Descriptions and Explainations of Works of Art, circa 1911 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Gunn Memorial Library, Washington, CT (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1913-1929 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Writings, Speeches, circa 1914 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Clippings, 1914-1942 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Brochures, 1908-1914 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Life of Christ Series (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, Regarding Exhibition, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Lists and Notes, circa 1924 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Clippings, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Pamphlet and Invitations for Exhibition, circa 1929 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Madison Square Presbyterian Church, New York City, NY (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1979; 1905-1910 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Clippings, circa 1910 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Pamphlets, circa 1910 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Morgan Library, New York City, NY (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1904; 1942 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Plans, Layout, circa 1907-circa 1930 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Writings, circa 1907 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Clippings, 1924-1927 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - St. John's Church, Washington, CT (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, circa 1910-1928 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Clippings, 1941; circa 1920 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Pamphlet, circa 1920 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Photographs, before 1940 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - University Club, New York City, NY, 1924; 1902-1904 (Box 3)
    - Writings, circa 1905 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Invitations, 1904-1905 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Clippings, circa 1904-1907 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - F. W. Vanderbilt House Murals, Hyde Park, NY (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1942; 1908 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Organization Files, 1904-1928; Series 7; 0.7 Linear feet Box 3-4, 13, 15-16
  This series contains records relating to Harry Siddons Mowbray's involvement with the American Academy in Rome, Commission of Fine Arts, and the Sculpture Commission of Connecticut. American Academy in Rome materials consist of organizational history notes, correspondence, printed materials, and photographs. The Commission of Fine Arts records contain correspondence, meeting minutes, reports and conclusions made by the commission, printed material, and sketches. Materials of note include those relating to the standardization of flag of the United States which consist of drawings and sketches, reports, and color samples of blue and red. There is also a report concerning the authenticity of a Titan painting, The Scultpure Commission of Connecticut material consists of appointment certificates, correspondence, lists, a resolution, and clippings.
  - American Academy in Rome (Box 3)
    - Organizational History Notes, circa 1904 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence, 1903-1919 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Brochures and Information Booklets, 1916; 1904-1907 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Clippings, 1905-1924 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Prints of Plans of Director's Residence, circa 1904 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Commission of Fine Arts (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1921-1928 (Box 3, Folder 53-55)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1923-1927 (Box 3, Folder 56-58)
    - Reports and Conclusions, 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 59-62)
      Includes flag standardization reports
    - "A Visit to the White House," probably by Harry Siddons Mowbray, 1923 November 15 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Clippings and Printed Materials for Memorials, 1921-1927 (Box 3, Folder 64-65)
      Oversized material housed in OV15-16
    - Sketches, Drawings, and Examples for Flag Standardization, circa 1925 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Color Samples for Flag Standardization, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Oversized Clippings and Flag Standardization Material, 1921-1928 (Box 15-16)
      Material from Box 3, F64-66
  - Sculpture Commission of Connecticut (Box 4)
    - Appointment Certificates, 1909-1925 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Oversized material housed in Box 13
    - Correspondence, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Lists, circa 1909 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Resolution, 1909 August 11 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, circa 1909 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Oversized Certificates, 1909-1925 (Box 13)
      Material from Box 4, F1
- Printed Material, 1876-1976; Series 8; 0.2 Linear feet Box 4, 16
  This series contains blank stationery and postcards, clippings, an issue of Collector's News, and exhibition announcements and catalogs
  - Blank Postcards, circa 1929 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Blank Stationery, circa 1890 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, circa 1900-1976 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
    Oversized material housed in OV16
  - Collector's News, 1876 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Includes article by Mowbray concerning egg collection
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1897-1976 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Oversized Clippings, circa 1900-1928 (Box 16)
    Material from Box 4, F8-9
- Photographs, circa 1874-circa 1928; Series 9; 4.7 Linear feet Box 4-14, 17-18
  This series contains two photo albums compiled by the Mowbray family, portraits and snapshots of Harry Siddons Mowbray, photos of homes and a studio. There are substantial photographs of works of art including glass plate negatives and lantern slides. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Photo Album, Fragment, circa 1890-1900 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - Photo Album, circa 1890-1914 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray, Portraits, 1883-circa 1928 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    1 glass plate negative; Housed in box 12
  - Harry Siddons Mowbray, with Colleagues and Friends, circa 1874-1925 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Homes, circa 1884 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Studios, circa 1885 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Works of Art (Box 5)
    - Works of Art, by Mowbray, circa 1900-1920 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Appellate Court, New York City, NY, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      6 glass plate negatives; Housed in box 11
    - Breckenridge Long House, St. Louis, MO, circa 1916 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Larz Anderson House, Washington, DC, circa 1916 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Oversized material housed in Box 14. 1 glass plate negative; Housed in box 11
    - Gunn Memorial Library, Washington, CT, circa 1910 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      8 glass plate negatives; Housed in box 8
    - University Club, New York City, NY, circa 1904 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
      14 glass plate negatives; Housed in boxes 11 and 12
    - Life of Christ Series, 1915-1925 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - St. John's Church, Washington, CT, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - St. Michael's Church, Litchfield, CT, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      4 glass plate negatives; Housed in box 11
    - Morgan Library, New York City, NY, 1905-1907 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Mrs. William Reese House, New Hamburg, NY, circa 1927 (Box 5, Folder 13)